Guide to the Chiapas Media Project Records TAM.774
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series III. Community Organizing, 1996-2011; 2.5 Linear Feet in 5 manuscript boxes
  - Aepoch Fund - Grant Paperwork, 2009 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Alexandra Halkin Bank Statements, 2008-2011 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Alexandra Halkin - Mexican Visa Paperwork, 1999-2000 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Amazon Watch Conference - Contacts Directory, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - American Anthropological Association 15th Annual Meeting, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - The Angelica Foundation - Grant Paperwork, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Asociacion de Medios de Comunicación (AMCIC) - Presentation, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Australian Indigenous Media - Resources from 2004 tour (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - "¡Ayuda A Chiapas! Help Chiapas!" - International Caravan to Chiapas Event Poster, Pastors for Peace and Caravana Mexicana Para Todos Todo, March, 1995 (Box Shared Tamiment 069, Folder 19)
  - Bi-National Educational Campaign on Migrant Workers in the Toxic Fields of Sinaloa - Grant Paperwork, 2008 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Bi-National Youth Video Production Teams, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Bi-National Youth Video Production Teams - Budgets and Receipts, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Camera Training Manuals, Undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Centro de Derechos Humanos Fray Bartolomé de las Casas - Microbus Contract, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Chiapas Media Project Banner by Josh MacPhee, 2000; cuid36394 (Box Shared Tamiment 154)
  - Chiapas Media Project - Budget Ledgers and Reports, circa 1998-2010; cuid36489
    - Paper Documents (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Electronic Records, TW_TAM_774_ER_6
  - Chiapas Media Project - Chicago Office Correspondence and Administrative Documents, 2008-2010 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Chiapas Media Project - General Information, 2005-2010 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Chiapas Media Project - Posters, Undated (Box 16, Folder 23, Flat-file-folder 6)
  - Chiapas Media Project Presentation Flyer, Savannah, Georgia, Undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Chiapas Media Project - Spanish Flyers, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Chiapas Youth Media Project, 1996-1998 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Chiapas Youth Media Project - Interview Translations, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Chiapas Youth Media Project - Letters of Support, 1996-1998 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Chiapas / United States Indigenous Video Exchange Project, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Community Human Rights Defenders Network, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - "Comunalidad y Autonomía" Bandana, Oaxaca, 2006-2007 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - "Confronting Globalization in Southern Mexico" Event, Buffalo, New York, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Consejo Latinoamericano de Cine y Comunicación de los Pueblos Indígenas (CLACPI), 2004-2006 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - "Contra El Silencio y El Olvido; La Voz de Los Pueblos Indigenas de Mexico" - Event Poster, Centro de Derechos Humanos de la Montaña, Chilpancingo, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - "Conversations Across Cultures: Mexican Ways of Knowing" Conference, Columbia University, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence with Donors, Festivals, and Universities, 1998-2007; cuid36490
    - Paper Documents (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Electronic Records, TW_TAM_774_ER_7
  - Cuentos Foundation Bank Statements, 2008-2010 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Cuentos Foundation Checkbooks, 2007-2009 (Box 15, Folder 5, 6)
  - Cuentos Foundation - Descriptive and Administrative Documents, 2007-2010 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Cultivo de Café Orgánico - Budget and Notes, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - European Initiative for Democracy and Human Rights - Grant Application, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Fair Food Across Borders Campaign - Budget Documents, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Festival Internacional de Video Documental, Venezuela, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Grant Research Notes, circa 2003 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Guerrero Video Productions and Workshops - Receipts, 2006-2008 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Guerrero Video Workshops - Description and Budgets, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - "In Our Own Image" Public Forum Flyer, Auckland, circa 2008 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Independent Media Conference, Marshall University, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Interview with Danny Glover and Stephanie Black re: Frantz Fanon, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Lakota-Anichinaabe Tour - Grant Paperwork, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Latin American Studies Association Congress, 2004-2007 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Letters of Recommendation and Support, 2000-2002 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Media Delegations - Evaluations, 1998-2000; cuid45231
    - Paper Documents (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Electronic Records, TW_TAM_774_ER_8
  - Media Delegations - Receipts, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Media Delegations - Release Forms, 1998-1999 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - "Mexico's Failed Drug War" Talk by Alexandra Halkin - Poster, Undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Millenium Delegation - Information Package, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - OURMedia: "Strengthening Citizens' Communication" Event, Barranquilla, Colombia, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Paco Vazquez Speaking Tour, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Peace and Justice Studies Association (PJSA) Conference, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Peace Development Fund - Grant Paperwork, 2002-2010 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Postcards and Indigenous Media Ephemera, circa 2000-2005 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Promedios Brochure Designs, 2000-2002; TW_TAM_774_ER_9
  - Proyecto Latinoamericano Presentation to the European Union, 2000; TW_TAM_774_ER_10
  - "Proyecto de Medios de Comunicacion en Chiapas" T-Shirts, Undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Rainforest Action Network - Grant Applicant Information, 2001; TW_TAM_774_ER_11
  - Receipts - Chiapas Media Centers, 2003-2006 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Receipts - Chicago Office, 2003-2010 (Box 9, Folder 2, 3)
  - Receipts - Equipment Purchases and Donations, 1998-2000 (Box 9, Folder 4, 5, 6, Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Receipts - Mexico Office, 1998-2002 (Box 10, Folder 2, 3, 4)
  - Receipts - OSI Grant, "Drug Policy" Conference, 2009 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Receipts - Travel, 1999-2008 (Box 10, Folder 6, 7)
  - Receipts - Travel, Equipment, and Supplies, 1998-2006 (Box 10, Folder 8, 9, 10, Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Receipts - Travel and Vehicle Repairs, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Receipts - USPS, 2008 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Red de Iniciativas Por el Video Indigena Latinoamericano (RIVIL) - Guggenheim Project, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Reducing Hunger and Food Insecurity in California's Rural and Farmworker Communities Roundtable, San Marcos, CA, March 10, 2010 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Reebok Human Rights Award Ceremony Program, 2005 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Reebok Human Rights Award Ceremony Recording, TW_TAM_774_ER_16
  - Reebok Human Rights Award Nomination for Carlos Perez Rojas, 2004 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Regional Media Centers - Global Knowledge Partnership (GKP) Grant, 2003-2004 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Requests for Funding, 2001; TW_TAM_774_ER_12
  - "Riding the Back of the Feathered Serpent / The Zapatista Struggle: Transformation Through Alternative Communication" Workshops, May, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - "The Right to Communicate is a Human Right" - Poster, WACC, UK, Undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Seminar on the Acquisition of Latin American Library Materials, Philadelphia, 2011 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Solidago Foundation - Grant Paperwork, 2001-2006 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - United Nations Workshop on Indigenous Media, 2000; cuid45229
    - Electronic Records, TW_TAM_774_ER_14
    - Paper Documentation (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - U.S. - Guerrero Community Video Project, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - U.S. - Mexico Fund for Culture Grant, 1999-2002 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - University Letters of Invitation for Screenings and Speaking Engagements, 2007 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Untitled Artwork, Beatriz Aurora, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Untitled Marker Drawing, Undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - ¡Va Por La Dignidad Rebelde! - Event Poster, Centro Universitario Cultural, Mexico City, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - "Video Fuels a Revolution" Lecture by Alexandra Halkin, Church Program, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Website Planning Documents, 2001; TW_TAM_774_ER_13
  - World Association for Christian Communication - Grant Paperwork, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Yuendumu Community Government Council - Media Clearance Policy and Contract, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Zapatista Figurine with Video Camera, Undated (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Zapatista Solidarity Group - Event Poster, November 17, 2005 (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Series IV. Written Works, 1998-2011; 2 Linear Feet in 3 manuscript boxes and 1 flat box
  This Series contains written works by and about the Chiapas Media Project, including press clippings, research publications, academic works, internal working files.
  - "Abused and Afraid in Ciudad Juarez" Report by Maureen Meyer, September, 2010 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - "Alternative Mediatique au Chiapas" by Carole Rieussec, Undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - American Indian License Agreement, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - "As Far From Sundance As Could Be" by Perla Ciuk, Undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - "Behind the Camera with the Chiapas Media Project," Real Screen, April, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - "Bolivian Filmmakers Record Indigenous Life" - Press, Albuquerque Journal, April 13, 2002 (Box Shared Tamiment 069, Folder 20)
  - "Chiapas La Resistencia," La Jornada, September 19, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - "Chiapas Media Project," Action, October, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - "Chiapas Media Project brings Chicagoans to Aguascalientes," StreetWise, August, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - "Chiapas Media Project builds connections with U.S. Natives," The Independent Native Journal, November 14, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Chiapas Media Project Pamphlets and Video Catalogs, circa 2000-2010 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Chiapas Media Project Postcards and Brochures, circa 2000-2010 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Chiapas Media Project Press Kit, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - "Chiapas Media Project puts video cameras in hands of villagers," Indian Country Today, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - "The Chiapas Media Project: Videos bring powerful stories of indigenous peoples in Mexico to campus," FVStakes, Spring, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - "Cinematic activism is enjoying a comeback," The Nation, April 2, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - "Comenzó el primer Festival Internacional de Cine y Derechos Humanos, en España," La Jornada, October 26, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - "Communal Interest and Political Decision-Making in an Emerging Mexican Indigenous Movement" by Martin Hébert, circa 2001 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - "Comparecen defensores comunitarios aute PGR," Cuarto Poder, September 4, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - "La Comunicación en manos de los pueblos indígenas", circa 2009 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - "Consolidan red de videoastas indígenas," La Jornada, October 13, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - "Creating Digital Dividends," BusinessWeek, December 8, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Crosscurrent: Uncompromising Television for the Information Age, October, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - "Crossing the Digital Divide," Illawarra Mercury, September, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - "Documental el Velo de Berta esta noche en La Quebrada," El Tiempo, September 30, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - "Don't Confuse Fashion with the Realities of Our Time," West Magazine, April 23, 2006 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - "Drug War Tragedy in Juarez," Current Anthropology Vol. 52 No. 6, December, 2011 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - "Educar desde la 'resistencia,'" Público, October 13, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - "Estrategias de Comunicación y Derechos Indígenas," CEFREC, 2000-2004 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - "Filming propaganda irresponsible" by Joseph Sternberg, October 17, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - "Films focus on the fight for justice," Metro Review, September, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - "Free Trade in the Americas: How Will it Impact YOU?!" by the Alliance for Responsible Trade (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - "Free Trade Unsettles Mexican Homeland," Northern Currents, October 19, 2005 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - "A Glowing Report from Taos New Mexico's 'Talking Pictures' Film Festival," iF Magazine, April 14, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - "Gaining Ground: Indigenous Video in Bolivia, Mexico, and Beyond" by Jeff Himpele, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - "La Gran Illusión… La Gran Frustración 1994-2004" - Proceso Magazine, January, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - "Group Efforts: Home movies from Mexico's rebellion," Chicago Reader, May 29, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - "Halkin Speaks About Diversity," The Bona Venture, November 5, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Handwritten Notes and Working Files, circa 1998-2010 (Box 12, Folder 32, 33, 34)
  - Handwritten Notes and Working Files, circa 1998-2010 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - "Human Rights Attorney Digna Ochoa Assassinated, Guerrero Environmentalists Freed", 2001; TW_TAM_774_ER_15
  - "Indigenous Film and Video in Latin America: Starting Points for Collection Development" by Daisy Dominguez, Undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - "Indigenous People Come Together," Indian Country Today, October 24, 2005 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - "Indigenous Resistances: A Look at the Chiapas Media Project" by Anna M. Brígido-Corachán, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - "Insta Ecologista Preso a Seguir Lucha Contra La Tala Ilegal," La Jornada, October 26, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Interview with Alex Halkin and Carlos Pérez Rojas, Undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - "La Isla", April 2007 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - "The Joy of Independent Cinema: The Arizona International Film Festival is Back…," Tucson Weekly, April, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Latin American Video Archives - Catalog, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Latin American Video Archives - Catalog Update, 2003 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - "Linking People with People" by Aimee Juan, The Vision, November 2005 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - "Llaman a la unidad por los bosques y la libertad de los ecologistas presos," La Jornada, November 24, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - "L'œil des Zapatistes," Il Manifesto, July 1, 2006 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - "Making Waves: Stories of Participatory Communication for Social Change" by Alfonso Gumucio Dagron, Undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - "Manual de Cabildeo," Movimiento de Cuidadano por la Democracia, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - "Media Representation and Indigenous Peoples" by Dr. Anne Pattel-Gray, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - "Mediated Development: Participatory Video and the Politics of Self-Representation in the Third World," by Melissa Brough, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - "Medios Indígenas e indigenistas," La Jornada, October 11 2005 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - "Mexican filmmakers describe their people's plight," The Green Bay News-Chronicle, April 14, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 19, Box 17, Folder 14)
  - "Migrantes Purepecha en Chicago," Voces Migrantes, 2006 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - "Migrating and Dying: Capitalist Agriculture…," Current Anthropology, Vol. 53 No. 2, April 2012 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - "La Mirada Indígena: Chiapas en Video," Contra Tiempo, October, 2005 (Box 13, Folder 9, Box 17, Folder 16)
  - "Miradas indígenas de América" Audiovisual Catalog, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - "Mobilizing Indigenous Video: the Mexican Case" by Laurel C. Smith, 2006 (Box 13, Folder 22, 23)
  - "Mujeres de Mundo," Multirevista No. 35, March, 2018 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - National Museum of the American Indian Magazine, Summer 2001 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - "Native Women Filmmakers Capture Hearts in Taos," Indian Country Today, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - "New Mexico in the Media," The Taos News, April 13, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - "Paco, Chiapas Media Project welcomed at Pine Ridge," News from Indian Country, November 14 2005 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - "Plan Nacional Indígena Originario de Comunicación Audiovisual," Bolivia, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - "Politico-Cultural Contacts Between Mexican Indigenous Groups…" by Martin Hébert, circa 2001 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - "Privilege has a cost," Gloucester Daily Times, June 30 1998 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - "Pro-TV Goes to Chiapas," Scanlines, Spring 1999 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - "Reading Indigenous and Mestizo Musical Instruments…" by Robert Neustadt, circa 2007 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - "Reel Lives," Night and Day, 2003 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - "Reel Lives," Style Weekly, October 8, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - "Reeling Them In: The Arizona International Film Festival aims to build audiences through cinematic diversity," Tucson Citizen, April, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - "Sanchez Shares Videos on Chiapas, Mexico," Midweek, April 14, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - "Sanctuary in Phoenix!" by Margery Leach, 2008 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - "Shining the Light on Chiapas," Street Scene, April 13, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - "S.I.T., Wild Root Sponsors three films from Chiapas", 2000 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - "The Socially Pro-Active Vacation: Tourists to the Rebellion," Spare Change, December, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - "Taos Talking Picture Festival Celebrates the Spirit of Independent Cinema," Tempo, April 13 2000 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - "Taos Touts Media Awareness…" indieWIRE, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - "Telling Their Own Stories," Bay Life, February 5 2004 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - "Telling Their Own Stories," The Tampa Tribune, February 5, 2004 (Box Shared Tamiment 069, Folder 21)
  - "Terror in Chiapas," The Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists, March-April 1998 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - "Through Their Own Eyes: the Chiapas Media Project" by Max Sussman, Clamor, March-April 2005 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Tracking: Community Media Network Publication, Autumn 1999 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - "'Tuvalu' Pleases at Talking Picture Festival," Pasatiempo, April 2000 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - "Unidos por una comunicación propia," Iquique, Chile, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - University of Oklahoma FVStakes Magazine, Spring 2003 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - "Via Video, Chiapas Natives Make Leap Into Modern World," Chicago Tribune, October 1, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - "Video, a Revolutionary Medium for Consciousness-Raising in Mexico…" Thesis by Claudia Magallanes Blanco, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - "Video Fuels a Cultural Revolution" by Alexandra Halkin, National Museum of the American Indian Magazine, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - "Video muestra la complicidad de la tv en el operativo de Atenco," La Jornada, June 18 2006 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - "Video Soldiers," Toward Freedom Magazine, January 2001 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - "Video technology brought to Mexico to record abuse," by Phyllis Ponvert, April 11 1998 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - "Videos of Resistance" by Kristinha M. Anding, July 2003 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - "Wild Spaces!" An enviro film festival," Greenhouse Living, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - "Xulum'Chon / El Dinosaurio," Sociedad Cooperativa Xulum'Chon, circa 2000 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - "Zapatistas, Chiapas Media Project, and Paco Vazquez," The Independent Native Journal, November 14 2005 (Box 14, Folder 21)